A Guide to the Jacob August Riis Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8156
Jacob August Riis Collection 1899-1914
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8156
13 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1965 October 21 ] 1966 January 13
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - Fragment, p. 13, beginning, "... clutching yet in his hand a torn, blood stained paper... ", AMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Jacob August Riis to Miss Ben Yassuf, 1899 December 9; ALS, 2 p.
    [Inquires about possibility of purchasing photographs of himself, taken by Miss Yassuf to send to his mother in Denmark. He thinks they are property of
    The Century
    so questions their availability. Praises her work and pluck."
  - Jacob August Riis to Dear Madame, 1901 November 1; ALS, 2 p.
    [Declines request for assistance because of lecture schedule; offers to send previous writing on kindergartens if they can be found; endorses kindergartens.]
  - Jacob August Riis to Dear Sir, 1903 September 15; ALS, 1 p.
    [Responds to request for his autograph. States his handwriting makes "printers weep."]
  - Jacob August Riis to My dear Sir, 1903 November 12; ALS, 1 p.
    [Apologizes and describes his heavy schedule including two nights in the White House, to which he looks forward because of his admiration for Theodore Roosevelt. Mentions Tony and the delivery of a barrel for him.]
  - Jacob August Riis to My dear Sir, 1903 November 18; ALS, 1 p.
    [Turns down Hartford lecture because of heavy lecture and travel commitments.]
  - Jacob August Riis to My dear Sir, 1906 June 10; ALS, 1 p.
    [Declines invitation. Will be working on the Pacific Coast. Refers to his Boston agent (Britt, 6 Beacon Street) to schedule engagements. Regrets lack of strength to do all that he would want.]
  - Jacob August Riis to Mr. Lewis, 1909 May 14; ALS, 1 p.
    [Agrees to autograph photographs. Suggests the one taken by Rockwood Photographers in New York. Expresses enthusiastic support for a Springfield Boys' Club. ]
  - Jacob August Riis to Mr. Lee, 1914 February 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Regrets that Lee was ill and had to leave Briar Brae. Mentions visiting Social Settlements in Boston, seeomg Dr. Denison formerly of Sea and Land Settlement in New York City and describes location of Denison's church. Offers introduction to Bishop Lawrence; suggests the best approach to literary work is to "write something you know of."]
- Photographs
  - Jacob August Riis seated, 1902 December; Photograph
  - Jacob August Riis head and shoulders, with printed biographical sketch, [1902 December]; Photograph
  - Jacob August Riis seated, n. d.; Magazine photograph